## Evan R. Wilson

9073 Gillman Street Livonia, MI 48150

(614)975-0621

Evan.R.Wilson23@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

High performing individual quick to master new technologies and processes in both cooperative and self-directed environments. Passionate for computer programming and engineering. Educated in various programming languages and efficient with problem solving and troubleshooting. Proven leadership and interpersonal skills with experience in business management.

# **Core Competencies**

● C#/C/C++

HTML/CSS

Python

- Object Oriented (oop)
- Visual Studio
- ASP.NET
- Computer Programming XAML/XML
- Web Development
- Regulatory Compliance
- Problem Solving
- Microcontrollers
- PHP Rubv
- Responsive content
- UI/UX

# **Professional Experience**

## American Red Cross Detroit, MI

2013-2017

### Lab Technician II

- Manufactured blood components and ensured successful fulfillment process based on client contracts.
- Maintained critical laboratory equipment up to federal regulatory standard for biologic medicine manufacturing.
- Performed quality assurance by supervising highly controlled processes and documentation.
- Trained manufacturing staff across multiple regions of business.
- Ensured compliance with laboratory regulations and Current Good Manufacturing Practices (CGMP).
- Developed relationships with various health system partners and provided excellent customer services.
- Managed logistics ensuring proper handling of biologic products, specimen samples, and patient documentation.

# Impero Coffee Roasters Columbus, OH

2011-2013

#### **General Manager**

- Managed retail business at multiple locations.
- Developed store policy and corresponding training for all employees.
- Maintained store cleanliness in accordance with Franklin County health code.
- Provided exceptional customer service and built rapport with high value wholesale clients.
- Created weekly employee schedule based on forecasted sales volume.
- Lectured Ohio State University Amnesty International Student Organization on an analysis of inequality in trade.

### Obama Organizing Fellows Columbus, OH

2008

## **Political Campaign Organizer**

- Received intensive campaign and community organization training.
- Recruited, trained, and managed 20-25 volunteers.
- Developed and implemented strategies to organize and mobilize communities by analyzing demographic data.
- Participated in public relations activities, both organizing and public speaking at political rallies.
- Acted as liaison between public and leadership by managing social media accounts.
- Set new records statewide records for daily voter registration and made concrete impacts on election outcome.

## Education

Henry Ford College Dearborn, MI

2016-Present

Bachelors of Science in Engineering (BSE) in Computer Science and Electrical Engineering

Columbus State Community College Columbus, OH

2012-2015

Associates of Arts in Political Science and International Studies.